

# JINU JOSEPH

## **About Me**

Highly motivated and enthusiastic Microbiologist with 5+ years' experience in Food and Feed Microbiology. Highly skilled in NABL Documentation and Maintenance of Microbiology Laboratory. Individual with both Team handling as well as team player skills.



8610401434



jinujose2395@gmail.com

#### **LANGUAGE**

- English
- Tamil (Fully Proficient)
- Malayalam (Basic)

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Britannia Industries Limited Bidadi Senior Executive - RECB February 2022 - January 2024

- Handling of Microbial Cultures (Bacteria, yeast and Mold)
- ISO 17025:2017 Documentation.
- Auditing of Cake production units for Air quality and monsoon compliance.
- Verification of documents for Ingredient specifications and drafting the same.
- Inventory management of the Microbiology Laboratory.
- Challenge study by mold culture in cakes to evaluate the efficiency of preservatives.
- Training of Internship students in Microbiology and food laboratory analysis and culture.
- Faced ISO 17025:2017(NABL) Audit.
- Collaboration with product development team for different projects.
- Training of quality and production team on the basics of Microbiology.
- HIRA and MSRA Implementation and Documentation.

## Kemin Industries South Asia Pvt Ltd Customer Laboratory Services Associate August 2019 - February 2022

- Handled numerous feed samples and raw materials with respect to Microbiological parameters in poultry, ruminant, aqua etc.
- Auditing of Feed mills for hygiene and product efficiency check.
- Worked in several projects including Probiotics, Yeasts etc.

## Scientific Food Testing Services Pvt Ltd (Aachi Masala) Executive Microbiologist July 2018 - August 2019

- Trained in performing various analyses of food, water, and environmental samples like swabs, and settle plate/air count.
- Experience in sampling of food, water, environmental samples
- ISO 17025:2015 Documentation
- Handling of Bacteria, Yeast, and Mold cultures.
- Participates in various ILC, IQC, and PT tests.
- Faced NABL Audit.
- Training of Summer Internship students.

## **CORE SKILLS**

- SOP and other document creation.
- NABL Documentation.
- Handling of Bacteria and Fungal cultures.
- Conducting ILC for differnt laboratories.
- Procurement of Critical Consumables.
- Auditing of Cake Plants and Feed Mills for Hygiene and Quality.
- Ingredient Specification for Raw materials.

## **EDUCATION**

ı	Mad	ras	Ch	ristiar	n Col	lege
	waa	103	$\sim$ 11	HISLIGI	1 601	ieue

M.Sc. Applied Microbiology

2018

75%

#### **Madras Christian College**

B.Sc Microbiology

2016

72%

## Infant Jesus Matric Higher Secondary

School

PUC 2013

78%

Infant Jesus Matric Higher Secondary

School

**SSLC** 

2011

80%

#### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the above statements are true to to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Jinu Joseph